Greg Weber

Experienced Software Engineer

Chicago, IL

☎ (650) 429 8122

⋈ greg+job@gregweber.info

†† github.com/gregwebs

In my current position as a hands-on manager and technical lead I have turned around a low-performing team into a lean, productive, and highly skilled team.

At my previous employer, I created the first version of their SaaS offering to deploy their distributed database that is now a focus of their business. At my current employer I am responsible for all cloud infrastructure. I hired and worked with another engineer to put all infrastructure under configuration management and make changes to upgrade our infrastructure to SOC 2 standards.

At a biotech company, I managed the infrastructure for the analytic component by writing code for services, getting infrastructure under the management of Terraform, and architecting to reduce our compliance burden.

	Experience
-	I have turned around a low performing team, introduced many best practices, and mentored engineers.
•	Cloud (AWS, GCP) and Kubernetes. Lead the creation of the first version of TiDB Cloud, a distributed cloud-hosted database.
• ,	HIPAA and SOC2. Developed documentation, process, architecture, and tooling to satisfy regulatory requirements. Currently undergoin a SOC 2 audit
Security	Enhancing security features, improving code quality for security, and developing a process for responding to security issues
Backend	Web applications, services, etc in Golang, Haskell, Ruby on Rails, and Python
Hard Problems	Developed a novel method to extract tabular data from PDFs. Worked to improve database security and performance stability: https://github.com/tikv/rfcs/pulls?q=is%3Apr+author%3Agregwebs
Static Safety	Introduced optional typing with MyPy (Python), TypeScript, and Flow (Javascript) as well as static analysis linters for Golang.
Web Frontend	Front end Javascript (TypeScript) experience. Great ability to make web UIs work well, but limited design abilities.

o https://eatnutrients.com a client-side React application I made

Programming Languages

Go Cloud, Kubernetes, and backend services programming. Created several libraries for better error handling.

- o https://github.com/gregwebs/errcode
- o https://github.com/gregwebs/go-recovery
- o https://github.com/gregwebs/errors (a fork)

0

Rust I have programmed professionally by contributing to the open source TiKV code base. I also authored the rust-process-iterator crate.

- https://github.com/tikv/tikv/pull/9647
- https://github.com/tikv/tikv/pull/9696/files
- o https://blog.gregweber.info/rust-process-iterator/

Javascript TypeScript in configuration management with Pulumi and AWS CDK. Frontend with React:

o https://github.com/gregwebs/StateTree a Statechart library

Haskell Programmed professionally and authored, maintained, or contributed to many highly used community libraries such as Persistent, Yesod, Shelly, and xss-sanitize.

- Yesod (web framework)
- Persistent (database "ORM")
- xss-sanitize (xss attack prevention)

Python Experience in pipeline, infrastructure, and analysis settings. I have successfully introduced MyPy, unit testing, and continuous integration into Python code bases.

Ruby I have developed Ruby on Rails application and published small Ruby gems in the past

Recent Positions

2022 - Now **Principal Engineer**, *Digital Mint*, Chicago.

I am a manager and technical lead in charge of all software development and responsible for its operation. I have turned around a low performing team, introduced many best practices, mentored engineers, and undergone a SOC 2 audit.

2018 – 2022 **Senior Cloud Engineer**, *PingCAP*, San Mateo.

I lead the development of the initial version of TiDB Cloud and continued with a focus on security and cloud integration. SOC2 compliance. Databases, cloud, Kubernetes. Most of my work was not on open source, but there are some open source contributions:

- o https://github.com/tikv/tikv/pull/9647
- o https://github.com/pingcap/tidb-operator/pull/789/files

2015 – 2018 Senior Software Engineer, Karius, Redwood City.

Lead software engineering of the production analytic component and infrastructure at this biotech company.

- Built a job flow controller that scaled up to thousands of machines and down to zero.
- Stabilized research grade software. Managed releases for the software powering the analysis of our diagnostic.
- Developed regulatory documentation
- o Involved with HIPAA compliance.

2015 Lead Engineer, Pivot Mail, San Jose.

A security company (encrypted email) that extensively used Haskell.

I was involved with improving infrastructure, making specifications, and release management. I got started on a project to cross-deploy a secure Haskell backend to different platforms before the company was wound down.

2013–2014 Lead Engineer, Docmunch, San Francisco.

Developed a novel PDF table extraction technique from first principles. Wrote frontend and backend web app code. The company was sold.

Education

2005 **B.S. ECE**, *University of Iowa*.

Publications

Shell scripting with type-safety using Haskell

Original article published in the German Linux Magazin.

Translated to English:

http://www.linux-magazin.de/Online-Artikel/

Shell-scripting-with-type-safety-using-Haskell/

Presentations

Functional Front End Coding

 $\verb|http://begriffs.com/posts/2015-11-30-functional-front-end-coding|.$

html

Shell scripting with Shelly

http://www.meetup.com/haskellhackersathackerdojo/events/91714772/

Building complex UIs with AngularJS

http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VxuN6WO3tIA

Publications